RG 062:030, Town of Columbia
Connecticut State Library
Town of Columbia records
1805-1940
Connecticut State Library
Columbia (Conn.)
13 cubic feet
Tax, election, financial and school records for the town of Columbia.
RG062_030
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of Columbia was incorporated in May 1804 and was taken from Lebanon.
Scope and Content
Tax, election, financial and school records for the town of Columbia.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Columbia -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Columbia -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Columbia -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Columbia -- Registers; School enrollment -- Connecticut -- Columbia -- Statistics; Voting registers -- Connecticut -- Columbia
Places:
Columbia (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Columbia (Conn.) -- Statistics, Vital
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1805-1940
  - T000895
    - Attachments, circa 1914-1940 (Box Box 1)
    - Lists of voters, 1880, 1925-1932 (Box Box 2)
    - Dog licenses, 1897-1920 (Box Box 2)
    - Personal tax rate books, 1921-1924 (Box Box 2)
    - Town tax rate books, 1911-1936 (Box Box 3)
    - School tax rate books, 1874-1903 (Box Box 4)
    - School district minute books, 1817-1921 (Box Box 4)
    - School registers, 1857-1871 (Box Box 5)
    - School bills, receipts, warnings of meetings, circa 1850-1900 (Box Box 5)
    - Burial, removal and transit permits, marriage licenses, birth certificates death certificates, sextons' returns, 1892-1934 (Box Box 6)
    - Account books, 2 volumes (Box Box 7)
      - 1805-1863 (Box Box 7)
      - 1837 (Box Box 7)
    - Order books, 2 volumes (Box Box 7)
      - 1898-1914 (Box Box 7)
      - 1926-1939 (Box Box 7)
    - Cash book, 1921-1939; 1 volume (Volume Item 7a)
    - Payment vouchers, 1934-1940 (Box Box 8)
    - Tax Abstracts
      - 1858, 1862, 1863, 1864; 1859, 1860, 1861; 1865, 1866, 1867, 1868, 1869, 1870; 1871, 1872, 1873, 1874, 1875 (Box Box 9)
      - 1876, 1877, 1878, 1879, 1880, 1881, 1882, 1883, 1884, 1885, 1886, 1887, 1888, 1889 (Box Box 10)
      - 1890, 1891, 1892, 1893, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899 (Box Box 11)
      - 1900, 1902, 1904, 1905, 1906, 1907 (Box Box 12)
      - 1908, 1919, 1910, 1911, 1912, 1913, 1914, 1915, 1916 (Box Box 13)
        On oversize shelving.
      - 1917, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925, 1926 (Box Box 14)
      - 1927, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1936 (Box Box 15)
    - Assessor's revaluation book, 1922; 1 volume (Volume Item 16)
    - Classified expenditures, 1914-1915; 1 volume (Volume Item 17)
    - Blueprints of Highway Department plan for proposed Route 14 between Columbia & Willimantic, 1934; 11 sheets (Volume Folder 1)
  - T003296
    - United States tax assessment list for Division 16 of Collection District I, 1862; 1 volume (Volume Oversize item)
      Includes Andover, Bolton, Columbia and Hebron.